On my journey with Akari,
we stopped by the port city of Libelle.
Off the coast of the city was a prison of fog with one
of the Four Major Human Errors sealed within:
The Pandemonium.
I attempted to trap Akari within the
Pandemonium to dispose of her,
but Akari used her Pure Concept of [Time]
to return as if nothing had happened.
Episode 8: Monstrine
It's so pretty!
Akari, don't stick yourself out like that.
It reminds me of when I almost
drowned a long time ago.
You fell in the ocean before, Menou?!
It was back when I was little, here in this city.
In Libelle? You never told me that!
I'm sure you were cute even if you were drowning!
Are you kidding?
Any other memories?
This was where I found out that Master Flare
was an Executioner who killed otherworlders.
Nothing in particular. It was a long time ago.
Café
There you are, Flarette.
Wow!
It's so lively!
It's not just tourists. The locals frequent this place, too.
It's probably the most crowded place in town.
Fish... Fruit...
What are those things?
They're etheric tools.
"Etheric tools"?
They're items that channel magecraft.
I think those were probably
unearthed from an ancient ruin.
Towns that are adjacent to the Wild Frontier
have these kinds of shops that-
Hey, Akari?!
Thank you!
Jeez, you're the one who asked the question.
Here, Menou. Open up!
Take that!
What?! It's so good!
It's watermelon.
Wait, watermelon?
It's a little different from the watermelon I know,
but yeah, I guess the flavor is close to watermelon...
What's different about the watermelon you know?
Let's see, it's usually red, though sometimes yellow...
That man... He looks like he's just walking,
And there are seeds all over,
but it's obvious he's monitoring us.
just enough so they don't get in the way of eating...
Invoke
[Flameshot]
Barrier
What is this, Menou?!
Please calm down, everyone.
Get down on the ground!
Why here, of all places?
Akari, will you hold this for me?
M-Menou! What do I do with this?!
Stop right there.
I would say you live up to your
name as Flare's apprentice,
but you forgot something important.
S-sorry, Menou...
You're part of the Fourth, aren't you?
This is an awfully aggressive welcome,
but what do you want?
We want to eliminate you of course, Flarette.
I see. So they're not after Akari.
How do you know who I am?
We got word that you thwarted some of our
comrades who were active in Grisarika.
We've had our eyes on you ever since.
You mean those terrorists on the train?
They were members of the Fourth, too?
Now that you mention it, I see the resemblance.
Like your amateurish tactics.
Why, you...
Don't you understand the situation you're in?!
Actually, you're the one who doesn't seem to understand.
That idiot is just a decoy.
Die, you!
You little...!
There.
That takes care of them.
Amazing as always, Menou!
Here!
Hey! Where are the ruffians?!
The knights are finally here.
Well, that was a surprise.
He did say he would attack her,
but I never thought it would be right after the meeting.
So that's Flarette.
I believe the other girl called her "Menou"?
Beautiful and strong... It hardly seems fair.
Oh, can I take this, please?
Those two are definitely going to talk, aren't they?
Besides...
He's the one who spoke ill
of my mother during the meeting.
Hey, what's wrong?!
What should we do now, Menou?!
Well, the church needs me there this evening, but-
What was that?
You stay here, Akari!
What happened?!
Th-they suddenly transformed into monsters...
"Monsters"?
That's delicious!
You may enter.
Excuse me.
You must be Ms. Menou.
Yes, Pastor Sicilia.
It's an honor to meet you.
No need for compliments.
I heard you made a big show of
fighting in the market earlier.
I did.
I can't say I'm impressed,
given you're an Executioner
with an otherworlder with you.
The situation was unavoidable.
And afterwards, I came across a number of odd things.
Is that so. But first, let's discuss this odd item here.
Expense Approval Form
Your approval form for travel funds...
It doesn't specify the most important detail:
how you intend to dispose of
your otherworlder companion.
Well...
You don't actually intend on taking
her to the Sanctuary, do you?
There's no such place that
"takes otherworlders in," after all.
I'm continuing to look for a way to kill her!
I promise I'll find a way before we get to the Sanctuary!
So you want more money for this journey
based on such an ambiguous promise?
You have got to be kidding me.
However, if it's a fair transaction where
I compensate you for your labor,
there might be a way.
I see, so the usual, then.
What do I need to investigate?
"Monstrine"?
Libelle
Yes, because it's "monstrous," I suppose.
It's a drug that's being dealt around
town that supposedly induces euphoria.
Here's a sample.
Wait, this etheric reaction...
It's sin magecraft!
Exactly.
And invoking sin magecraft most often
involves a human body, spirit, or soul.
Which means...
...there are people being sacrificed.
How despicable.
Yes...
But the odd thing is that there are very few
people who have gone missing in this city.
Maybe they were just never reported missing?
That's not all that's odd.
I actually got attacked by the Fourth earlier.
What?! Really?
After they got captured they turned into monsters.
According to Pastor Sicilia,
it has something to do with this "monstrine."
Why would they turn some of their own?
In any case, we have to investigate.
For the sake of travel funds, as well.
Could you look into the supply chain, Momo?
Sure.
I'm happy to do anything that makes
things easier for you, Menou.
Though it really ticks me off that it's for
your journey with that stupid set of boobs!
Thank you, Momo.
More! I want more pats on the head!
While you're looking into that,
I'll investigate from a different angle.
Libelle
What?! I can't see anything in front of me!
Oh, come on...
Whoops?
Splash! Shake shake shake.
Good morning, Menou!
You got away!
Akari...
Were you planning to crush me
to death with your weight?
Excuse me?!
You were taking so long to get up,
so I just figured I'd wake you up!
I'm sure there were better ways to wake me up.
I got carried away with my love for you!
Hey, owww!
But it's so unusual, you know? You waking up so late!
Well, I suppose so.
Is it because the pastor wanted you at the church?
Did you two get up to some "fun" last night?
Ow!
Oof...
The figurehead of the Fourth in this city, Manon Libelle...
I need to find a way to investigate her affairs...
But how?
Lady Manon, you're the one who suggested
we distribute that monstrine!
Yes, that's quite correct.
Monstrine provides euphoria and is
highly addictive to those who take it.
That's what you said when you brought
in that etheric tool for producing it!
Yes, the drug for distribution has
been adjusted to be that way.
Not only is it a way to fund our activities,
but those who take it can potentially be
used as hostages to stave off the Faust.
As a final resort,
we could turn them into monsters
and use them as weapons.
That's what you said.
I did.
In that case, why did Kaiser turn into a monster?!
He's a member of our council!
Kaiser...?
Oh, you mean the man from yesterday!
The reason is simple enough.
I laced the food I served during
the meetings with monstrine.
What?!
What have you done?!
Why you little...!
You won't get away with this!
Ether: Living Sacrifice - Chaos Adhesion
Pure Concept [Chaos] - Summon
[Tangled Jump Rope]
So, um, are there any other complaints?
You're a failure who never inherited your mother's power.
How dare you?
It's simple, really.
A certain individual asked me to spread monstrine,
in return for help in enacting my revenge.
"Revenge"?
Flarette, the apprentice to Flare, who killed my mother.
Once I knew she was coming,
it was only natural that I wanted to give her a
"proper" welcome, don't you think?
I'm making all kinds of arrangements,
so I do hope you'll all cooperate.
Hey, cut that out! What did we ever do to you?!
Like I said, just tell me what you know.
You lot are the dregs of society.
You must have used monstrine, no?
W-we've got nothin' to do with that!
Our leader told us never to touch the stuff!
A delinquent leader with morals?
I'd love to see the person's face!
This way, Leader!
I know, calm down.
Wait, this voice...
Hey, whoever you are,
I won't have you messing with my...
Well, if it isn't Momo!
To think we'd reunite in a place like this!
You die here, crappy little princess!
I must say, I'm so glad we get to talk like this, Momo.
Once my initial surprise attack failed,
I knew prolonging the fight would
only please you, Little Princess.
You've come to know me too well, Momo.
Why couldn't you have died in those ruins?!
Oh, those gargoyles there were quite a challenge.
Enemies based on the concept
of original sin are troublesome.
I'm especially poorly matched against demons.
Because your only strategy is brute force.
Though gargoyles are inferior,
just stone statues with demons infused in them.
They're actually closer to monsters than demons.
Oh, is that so?
They're inanimate objects that had their
composition changed by taking in demons.
Monsters are basically creatures that have
mutated by taking in original sin, after all.
I never gave thought to what monsters might be.
Of course you didn't, Little Princess.
Well, until about a thousand years
ago before sin magecraft existed,
demons and monsters didn't even exist, you know?
What happened a thousand years ago?
There's no reason I should have to explain this, but fine.
You know the Pandemonium that's
off the coast of this city?
Yes, it's the fog that has one of the
Four Major Human Errors sealed within.
That Human Error was originally a
very young girl from another world.
With her Pure Concept,
the girl's fantasies materialized into demons,
and the blood and flesh that
fell from her became monsters.
An inferior imitation of her Pure Concept [Chaos]
became what we know as sin magecraft.
In other words,
the thing sealed within the Pandemonium is the
very source of the monsters that ravage our world.
I see.
But anyway, why are you playing boss to those lowlifes?
They're actually quite candid and likable.
And why were you picking on them, Momo?
I was just looking for info on monstrine.
By the way, I hear you told them to stay away from it.
Indeed. I saw the Fourth trying to deal it to them.
That stuff is bad news.
Aw, I see.
You aren't famous for going around righting
wrongs for nothing, Princess Justice.
But you couldn't bear to put up with it either, am I wrong?
Isn't that why you were so intent on your investigation?
Shall I share my information with you?
I already have a lead to where
the drug is being produced.
I can find that out myself, thank you!
You don't want to be in my debt?
Then what if we strike a deal instead?
I'll give you my information if you'll compete with
me to see who's infiltration gets better results.
Excuse me?
I'm planning to investigate a different place.
The prime suspect behind the distribution
of monstrine is Manon Libelle,
and this is the invitation to a
ball she's hosting tomorrow evening.
I don't think you're at all cut out to infiltrate
or investigate anything, Little Princess!
I'm capable in everything I do.
I'm confident in my ability to
sniff out a target's vulnerabilities.
"Sniff out"? That sure sounds impractical!
You'll compete if you're so confident, then?
Let us see who manages to get more information.
We'll meet back here at midnight tomorrow.
So anyway, that crappy little princess was alive.
How did she wind up as the
boss of some delinquents?
Well, it's impressive she found out
where the drug is being produced.
I'm sure she just has too much time on her hands.
More importantly, about Manon Libelle's evening ball...
I have information on that already.
Pastor Sicilia arranged for me to get an invitation.
I'll have to be careful if the princess is attending as well,
but I'm just going as a nameless
priestess accompanying the pastor,
so there shouldn't be any-
No, you can't! You have to let me make a dress for you!
You're going to spy on the enemy!
Why would you dress so obviously
like a priestess in enemy territory?!
And more importantly,
dressing you up is a mandatory requirement!
But it's tomorrow evening.
There's no time to be making a dress.
One night is all I need!
It's decided, then! Okay, I have to go now!
Oh well. She doesn't listen once she's in that mode.
Speaking of not listening, there's that other one...
I want to go, too!
I'm going!
You get to go into that castle, right?
And only you get to go? It's so not fair!
It's not a matter of fairness. It's for work!
What if I get abducted while you're gone?!
I'll at least say a prayer to our Lord
for the precious life that was lost.
What?! That's super mean!
It's not like you have anything you
could wear to a ball, anyway!
I have my school uniform, okay?
I wanna go! I wanna go! I wanna go!
Come on, you know you can't afford to stand out.
Let's see, I wonder where my darling Menou could be...
That's Pastor Sicilia there.
Which must mean somewhere nearby...
Ooh! There she is! Aww, she's so lovely!
I just love it when she's all dressed up!
Thank you so much Pastor Sicilia,
for allowing such an unreasonable request.
I don't mind.
It's better if no one can tell you're a priestess,
and whatever you decide to wear-
No, not about that.
What?! Why?!
Why is Boobalicious there?!
Menou! How do I look?
I'm a pure, just, and strong priestess!
Um, Pastor Sicilia...
Thank you for arranging an invitation for Akari as well...
I must say I'm a little worried,
but she's your responsibility.
Excuse me.
Hey! Wait for me, Menou!
Why does Boobalicious get to see Menou in the
dress I made for her up close when I don't?!
I can't take this!
If I want to quell this rage I'm feeling,
I have to destroy the place they
produce monstrine at the very least!
Thank you so much for coming, everyone.
I do hope you'll enjoy the evening.
I've prepared a plentiful feast for you to enjoy as well.
Manon Libelle...
Next Episode
At the Evening Ball
Next episode: At the Evening Ball